The new James Bond...living on the edge.
The Living Daylights is a action, adventure,
thriller film directed by John Glen.
After a defecting Russian general reveals a plot to assassinate foreign spies, James Bond is assigned a secret mission to
dispatch the new head of the KGB to prevent an escalation of tensions between the Soviet Union and the West.
James Bond, played by Timothy Dalton.
Kara Milovy, played by Maryam D'Abo.
Brad Whitaker, played by Joe Don Baker.
Kamran Shah, played by Art Malik.
General Leonid Pushkin, played by John Rhys-Davies.
General Georgi Koskov, played by Jeroen Krabbé.
The Living Daylights is a 1987 spy film, the fifteenth entry in the James Bond series produced by Eon
Productions, and the first of two to star Timothy Dalton as the fictional MI6 agent James Bond.
The fourth film in the series to be directed by John Glen, the film's title is taken from Ian Fleming's short
story "The Living Daylights", the plot of which also forms the basis of the first act of the film.
It was the last film to use the title of an Ian Fleming
story until the 2006 instalment Casino Royale.
It is also the first film to have Caroline Bliss as
Miss Moneypenny, replacing Lois Maxwell.
The Living Daylights was produced by Albert R.
Broccoli, his stepson Michael G.
Wilson, and co-produced by his daughter, Barbara Broccoli.
It grossed $191.2 million worldwide and was followed by Licence to Kill in 1989.
The film explores themes of prison, london,
england, assassination, airplane, escape.
The tone is intense.